Chandler, Alfred D., 1918-2007. Papers, 1941-2004: A Finding Aid
Alfred D. Chandler papers, 1940-2007
- Series IV. Harvard Business School, Emeritus, 1973-2007
  - Subseries A. HBS Emeritus Correspondence and Subject Files 1973-2007
    - Free Press: Robert Wallace, 1990-1995 (Box 216, f. 20)
    - Freyer, Tony, 1987-1993 (Box 176, f. 9)
    - Fruin, Mark, 1993-1997 (Box 176, f. 10)
    - Fruin, Mark, 1991-1997 (Box 216, f. 21)
    - G, 1991-1995 (Box 176, f. 11-12)
    - G, 1999-2001 (Box 176, f. 13)
    - Galambos, Louis, 1991-1996 (Box 176, f. 14)
    - Gavin, David (on GM), 2005 (Box 216, f. 22)
    - Grandy, Anthony (Box 176, f. 15)
    - Grey, Martin, 1990-2001 (Box 177, f. 1-2)
    - Giebelhaus, A., 1986 (Box 177, f. 3)
    - Graham, Margaret, 1988 (Box 177, f. 4)
    - H, 1978, 1989-1997 (Box 177, f. 5-6)
    - H, 1996-2002 (Box 177, f. 7)
    - Hagley Museum and Library, 1991-1995 (Box 177, f. 8-11)
    - Hagley Museum and Library, 1997-2002 (Box 177, f. 12)
    - Hagley Museum and Library, 2005 (Box 217, f. 1)
    - Hannah, Leslie, 1992-2000 (Box 177, f. 13)
    - Harding, Robert J. (Box 177, f. 14)
    - Harvard 65th Reunion, 2005 (Box 217, f. 2)
    - HBS Press: Rights and Royalties, 1990-1997 (Box 177, f. 15)
    - HBS Press: Rights and Royalties, 1990-1997 (Box 178, f. 1)
    - HBS Press: Rights and Royalties, 1998-2006 (Box 217, f. 3-5)
    - Henderson, Albert (convict), 2004 (Box 217, f. 6)
    - Hikino, Takashi, 1993-2000 (Box 178, f. 2)
    - Hitotsubashi Business Review, 2006 (Box 217, f. 7)
    - Holland, Max, 1989-1994 (Box 217, f. 8)
    - Hoover, Gary (Hoover's Vision), 2004 (Box 217, f. 9)
    - Horwitch, Mel, 1995 (Box 217, f. 10)
    - Hounshell, David, 1991-1995 (Box 178, f. 3)
    - Hyman, Louis, 2006 (Box 217, f. 11)
    - I, 1994-1998 (Box 178, f. 4)
    - Ines Barbero, Maria 1995 (Box 217, f. 12)
    - Inter-Collegiate Yacht Racing Association of North America., 1998 (Box 217, f. 13)
    - Irwin: Royalty Reports, 1991-1995 (Box 178, f. 5)
    - J, 1995-1997 (Box 178, f. 6)
    - Japan Academy; 1993 (Box 178, f. 7)
    - John, Richard, 1992-1999 (Box 178, f. 8)
    - John, Richard, 1990-2000 (Box 217, f. 14-19)
    - Jones, Geoffrey, 1991-2002 (Box 178, f. 9)
    - Jones, Geoffrey, 2002-2004 (Box 218, f. 1-2)
    - Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization, 1991-1993 (Box 178, f. 10)
    - Journal of Economic History, 2002 (Box 218, f. 3)
    - K, 1991-1999 (Box 178, f. 11)
    - K, 1998-2001 (Box 178, f. 12)
    - Kapoor, Al, 2006 (Box 218, f. 4)
    - Kaufman, Allen, 1987-1989 (Box 178, f. 13)
    - Kaufman Foundation, 2006 (Box 218, f. 5)
    - Kawabe, Nobuo, 1991-1993 (Box 178, f. 14)
    - Kimball, Peter (traveling fellowship-US scholars), 2004 (Box 218, f. 6)
    - Kleiner, Art, 2002 (Box 218, f. 7)
    - Knights, Peter, 1988-1995 (Box 178, f. 15)
    - Kobrak, Christopher, 1994-1997 (Box 178, f. 16)
    - Kocka, Jürgen, 1991-1994 (Box 178, f. 17)
    - Kogut, Bruce, 1993-1998 (Box 178, f. 18)
    - Konvitz, Josef, 1994 (Box 178, f. 19)
    - Kouri, Emilio, 1991 (Box 218, f. 8)
    - Kouri, Emilio, 1992-1994 (Box 178, f. 20)
    - Kransdorff, Arnold, 1992-1994 (Box 178, f. 21)
    - Kutler, Stanley, 1991 (Box 217, f. 9)
    - L, 1991-1996 (Box 179, f. 1-2)
    - L, 1998-2003 (Box 179, f. 3)
    - Lamoreaux, Naomi, 1986-1992 (Box 179, f. 4)
    - Lamdau, Ralph, 1992-2000 (Box 179, f. 5)
    - Larson, John, 1987-1988 (Box 179, f. 6)
    - Lazonick, William, 1994-1997 (Box 179, f. 7)
    - Lee, Frederic S., "Directing Economic Research, Philanthropic Foundations and the Rehabilitation of Big Business, 1934-1977" (Box 179, f. 8)
    - Leffler, William, 1994-1996 (Box 179, f. 9)
    - Lehmann, Michael B., 1986-1991 (Box 179, f. 10)
    - Levy-Leboyer, Maurice, 1990-1992 (Box 179, f. 11)
    - Licht, Walter, 1986-1991 (Box 179, f. 12-13)
    - Lipartito, Ken, 2003-2004 (Box 218, f. 10-11)
    - Loescher, Samuel, 1991 (Box 179, f. 13)
    - Longwood Gardens, 2004 (Box 218, f. 12)
    - Loria, Louis, 2005-2006 (Box 218, f. 13)
    - Loring, Ian, 1991 (Box 179, f. 14)
    - Mc, 1992-1998 (Box 179, f. 15)
    - Mc, 2000-2003 (Box 179, f. 16)
    - McCraw, Thomas, 1991-1999 (Box 179, f. 17)
    - M, 1998-2002 (Box 179, f. 18)
    - M, 1990-1996 (Box 179, f. 19-20)
    - MIT Press (Box 179, f. 21)
    - Made in America, 1993 (Box 179, f. 22)
    - Mahler, Walter, 1993-1994 (Box 180, f. 1)
    - Mahoney, Joseph, 1993-1994 (Box 180, f. 2)
    - Marris, Robin, 1998 (Box 180, f. 3)
    - Marshev, Vadim, 2004 (Box 218, f. 14)
    - Massachusetts Audubon Society gifts, 2004 (Box 218, f. 15)
    - Massachusetts Historical Society, 2004 (Box 218, f. 16-17)
    - Mason, Mark, 1993 (Box 180, f. 4)
    - Mass, William, 1989-1993 (Box 180, f. 5)
    - Mathis, Franz, 1991-1994 (Box 180, f. 6)
    - Mazlish, Bruce, 1996-203 (Box 180, f. 7)
    - Mazzoleni, Roberto, 1994 (Box 180, f. 8)
    - Miranti, Paul, 1990-1997 (Box 180, f. 9)
    - Miranti, Paul, 2003-2007 (Box 218, f. 18)
    - Miranti, Paul, 2004-2006 (Box 219, f. 1-2)
    - Morgenson, Bettina, 1999-2000 (Box 180, f. 10)
    - Morgenstern, Mark, 1993 (Box 180, f. 11)
    - Morikawa, Hidemasa, 1990-2001 (Box 180, f. 12)
    - Morikawa, Hidemasa, 1998 (Box 219, f. 3)
    - Mowery, David, 1998-1990 (Box 180, f. 13)
    - N, 1992-2002 (Box 180, f. 14)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1991 (Box 180, f. 15)
    - National Science Foundation, 1990-1994 (Box 180, f. 16)
    - Nazzo, Jim (Box 180, f. 17)
    - Nelson, Richard, 1991-1994 (Box 180, f. 18)
    - New England Quarterly, 1998-2000 (Box 180, f. 19)
    - New England Quarterly, 2002 (Box 219, f. 4)
    - Nonprofit Management and Leadership: Interview of Alfred D. Chandler, 1993 (Box 180, f. 20)
    - O, 1990-1991 (Box 180, f. 21)
    - O, 2000-2002 (Box 180, f. 22)
    - Office of Technology Assessment, 1993-1994 (Box 181, f. 1)
    - Oxford University Press, 1985-2004 (Box 181, f. 2)
    - Oxford University Press, P.S. Du Pont, 1998 (Box 181, f. 3)
    - Oxford scholarship, 2003 (Box 219, f. 5)
    - P, 1991-2003 (Box 181, f. 4)
    - Pacem Productions, 2003 (Box 219, f. 6)
    - Perkins, Edwin; 1993-1997 (Box 181, f. 5)
    - Permissions, 1991-2001 (Box 181, f. 6)
    - Permissions, 2002-2006 (Box 219, f. 7)
    - Peretti, Fabrizio, 2000 (Box 181, f. 7)
    - Pine, Carol, 1992-1995 (Box 181, f. 8)
    - Porter, Michael, 1991-1992 (Box 181, f. 9)
    - Prechel, Harland, 1996-1997 (Box 181, f. 10)
    - Previts, Gary, John, 1992-1994 (Box 181, f. 11)
    - Pugh, Emerson, 1993-1994 (Box 181, f. 12)
    - R, 1991-1996 (Box 181, f. 13)
    - R, 1998-2002 (Box 181, f. 14)
    - Raff, Daniel, 1991-1997 (Box 181, f. 15)
    - Reviews by Chandler, circa 1989 (Box 246, f. 18)
    - Roberts, Keith, 1993-2004 (Box 219, f. 8)
    - Robertson, Paul (Box 181, f. 16)
    - Rodrigues, Jorge Nascimento, Interview of Alfred D. Chandler, 2000-2002 (Box 181, f. 17)
    - Roof, Hilton; 1989 (Box 181, f. 18)
    - Rousmaniere, John, 1992-1996 (Box 181, f. 19)
    - S, 1990-1997 (Box 181, f. 20-21)
    - S, 1998-2003 (Box 181, f. 22)
    - Salsbury, Stephen, 1994-1997 (Box 182, f. 1)
    - Samuelson, Robert, 2006 (Box 219, f. 9)
    - Samuelsson, Christer, 1999-2000 (Box 182, f. 2)
    - Sapelli, Giulio, 1992-1994 (Box 182, f. 3)
    - Saussois, Jean-Michel, 1990-1994 (Box 182, f. 4)
    - Scale and Scope Reviews, 1990-1993 (Box 182, f. 5-11)
    - Scale and Scope Translations, 1991-1992 (Box 182, f. 12)
    - Schröter, Harm, 1994-1996 (Box 182, f. 13)
    - Scheifer, Andrei, 1990 (Box 182, f. 14)
    - Severson, David (adult learning), 2003 (Box 219, f. 10)
    - Shaw, George, 1995 (Box 219, f. 11)
    - Shiman, Daniel, 1991-1992 (Box 182, f. 15)
    - Shin, John (translation in Korean), 2006 (Box 219, f. 12)
    - Sicilia, David, 1990-1998 (Box 182, f. 16)
    - Sicilia, David, 2003 (Box 219, f. 13)
    - Silver, Morris, 1997 (Box 182, f. 17)
    - Simon and Schuster, 1999 (Box 182, f. 18)
    - Simon and Schuster, 2000 (Box 219, f. 14)
    - Sklar, Martin, 1993 (Box 182, f. 19)
    - Sloan Foundation, 1997-1998 (Box 182, f. 20)
    - Smith, Michael, 1993 (Box 182, f. 21)
    - Smith, Robert, 2003 (Box 219, f. 15)
    - Smoler, Frederick, Interview of Alfred D. Chandler, undated (Box 182, f. 22)
    - Sonnenfeld, Jeffery, 1991-1998 (Box 182, f. 23)
    - Silva de Sousa, Luis, 1994-1995 (Box 183, f. 1)
    - St. Botolph Club, 2004 (Box 219, f. 16)
    - Standard and Poor's 145th, 2005 (Box 219, f. 17)
    - Steinbock, Dan, 1996-1997 (Box 183, f. 2)
    - Strategic Management Journal, 1988-1989 (Box 219, f. 18)
    - Strategic Management Journal, 1991-1998 (Box 183, f. 3)
    - Strategic Management Society, 2005 (Box 219, f. 19)
    - Strouse, Jean, 1991-1995 (Box 183, f. 4)
    - Sturchio, Jeffery, 1990 (Box 219, f. 20)
    - Sylla, Richard, 1986-1989 (Box 183, f. 5)
    - T, 1991-1997 (Box 183, f. 6)
    - T, 1998-2001 (Box 183, f. 7)
    - TRW, History Advisory Committee, 1991-1993 (Box 183, f. 8)
    - Teece, David, 1991-2003 (Box 183, f. 9)
    - Teece, David, 2003-2004 (Box 220, f. 1)
    - Teichova, Alice, 1997-2000 (Box 183, f. 10)
    - Thomson, Ross, 1989-1993 (Box 220, f. 2-4)
    - Thomson, Ross, 1991-1992 (Box 183, f. 11)
    - Thompson Learning, 1999-2001 (Box 183, f. 12)
    - U, 1991 (Box 183, f. 13)
    - Uda, Osama, 1999-2002 (Box 183, f. 14)
    - Usselman, Steven, 1991-1999 (Box 183, f. 15)
    - V, 1990-1997 (Box 183, f. 16)
    - V, 1998-2002 (Box 183, f. 17)
    - van der Bergh, Lucia, 2002 (Box 183, f. 18)
    - van der Wee, Herman, 1991-2000 (Box 183, f. 19)
    - Voluntas Articles, 1996, Photocopies (Box 183, f. 20)
    - vom Brocke, Bernard, 1992 (Box 183, f. 21)
    - von Norden, Andrew, 2003 (Box 219, f. 5)
    - W, 1991-1997 (Box 183, f. 22)
    - W 1999-2003 (Box 183, f. 23)
    - WGBH, The Prize, 1991 (Box 183, f. 24)
    - WQED, Making of America-Series Advisory Committee, 1993 (Box 183, f. 25)
    - Walker, Juliet E.K., 1989 (Box 184, f. 2)
    - Wallace, Robert, 1991-2000 (Box 220, f. 6-7)
    - Wanda, Kazuo, 1999-2002 (Box 184, f. 1)
    - Warsh, David, 2005 (Box 220, f. 8)
    - Wordley, Teter, 1991-1997 (Box 184, f. 3)
    - Webb, Allen, 1991-1996 (Box 184, f. 4)
    - Weeks, Stuart, 1991 (Box 184, f. 5)
    - Westney, Eleanor, 1985 (Box 184, f. 6)
    - Whitten, David, 1991-1993 (Box 184, f. 7)
    - Whittington, Richard, 1999-2001 (Box 184, f. 8)
    - Wilkens, Mira (Box 184, f. 9)
    - Williams, Ike, 2003 (Box 220, f. 9)
    - Woodman, William, 1997 (Box 184, f. 10)
    - XYZ, 1992-1996 (Box 184, f. 11)
    - XYZ, 1999-2002 (Box 184, f. 12)
    - Yadin, Orly (Box 184, f. 13)
    - Yates, JoAnne, 1990-1994, 2004 (Box 220, f. 10-12)
    - Yeager, Mary (Kujovich), 1999-2001 (Box 184, f. 14)
    - Yudanov, Andrei, 1996-2003 (Box 184, f. 15)
    - Yudanov, Andrei, 1998-2003 (Box 220, f. 13)
    - Yonekura, Sei, 1992-2003 (Box 184, f. 16)
    - Zachary, G. Pascal, 1995-1996 (Box 184, f. 17)
    - Correspondence, Summer 1989 (Box 221, f. 1)
    - Correspondence, Jan.-April 1992 (Box 184, f. 18)
    - Correspondence, June 1992 (Box 184, f. 19)
    - Correspondence, July-Aug. 1992 (Box 184, f. 20)
    - Correspondence, Sept.-Oct. 1992 (Box 184, f. 21)
    - Correspondence, Nov. 1992 (Box 184, f. 22)
    - Correspondence, Dec. 1992 (Box 184, f. 23)
    - Correspondence, Jan. 1993 (Box 184, f. 24)
    - Correspondence, Feb.-March 1993 (Box 184, f. 25)
    - Correspondence, April 1993 (Box 184, f. 26)
    - Correspondence, May-June 1993 (Box 184, f. 27)
    - Correspondence, Aug.-Dec. 1993 (Box 184, f. 28)
    - Correspondence, Sept. 1993 (Box 184, f. 29)
    - Correspondence, Oct.-Dec. 1993 (Box 184, f. 30)
    - Correspondence, Jan.-Feb. 1994 (Box 185, f. 1)
    - Correspondence, March-April 1994 (Box 185, f. 2)
    - Correspondence, May-June 1994 (Box 185, f. 3)
    - Correspondence, Aug.-Sept. 1994 (Box 185, f. 4)
    - Correspondence, Oct. 1994 (Box 185, f. 5)
    - Correspondence, Nov-Dec. 1994 (Box 185, f. 6)
    - Correspondence, Jan.-April 1995 (Box 185, f. 7)
    - Correspondence, May-Aug. 1995 (Box 185, f. 8)
    - Correspondence, Sept.-Dec. 1995 (Box 185, f. 9)
    - Correspondence, 1995-1998 (Box 221, f. 2)
    - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 221, f. 3)
    - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 221, f. 4)
    - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 221, f. 5)
    - Correspondence, 2002 (Box 221, f. 6)
    - Correspondence, Jan.-June, 2003 (Box 221, f. 7)
    - Correspondence, July-Dec., 2003 (Box 221, f. 8)
    - Correspondence, Jan.-March, 2004 (Box 221, f. 9)
    - Correspondence, Apr.-June, 2004 (Box 221, f. 10)
    - Correspondence, July-Sept., 2004 (Box 221, f. 11)
    - Correspondence, Oct.-Dec. 2004 (Box 221, f. 12)
    - Correspondence, Oct. 2004 unanswered (Box 221, f. 13)
    - Correspondence, Dec. 2004 (Box 221, f. 14)
    - Correspondence, Jan.-June, 2005 (Box 221, f. 15)
    - Correspondence, Summer 2006 (Box 221, f. 16)
    - Correspondence, 2007 (Box 221, f. 17)
    - Email, 2002 (Box 221, f. 18)
    - Email, 2003 (Box 222, f. 1)
    - Email (Chinese and Indian corresp.), 2003 (Box 222, f. 2)
    - Email, 2004 (Box 222, f. 3)
    - Email, 2005 (Box 222, f. 4-5)
    - Email, Summer 2005 (Box 222, f. 6)
    - Email, Oct. 2005 (Box 222, f. 7)
    - Email, Dec. 2005-2006 (Box 222, f. 8)
  - Subseries B. HBS Emeritus Research and Writings, 1988-2005
    This subseries consists of material related to research and writing projects undertaken by Alfred Chandler while Professor Emeritus at HBS including, Inventing the Electronic Century: The Epic Story of the Consumer Electronics and Computer Industries (2001) and Shaping the Industrial Century: The Remarkable Story of the Evolution of the Modern Chemical and Pharmaceutical Industries (2005). The research material includes notes, photocopies of primary and secondary research material, newspaper clippings, corrected drafts, and correspondence concerning the works, including comments from others who have read Chandler's manuscripts. Also includes some materials related to the publications Business History Around the World (2003), Leviathans (2005), and other academic papers and articles.
    Primarily arranged chronologically by date of publication.
    - "Managerial Enterprise and Competitive Capabilities," Business History, Vol. 34, No. 2 [pub. Oct. 1991] (Box 226, f. 9-10)
    - "Corporate Strategy, Structure and Control: Methods in the United States During the 20th Century," Industrial and Corporate Change, [pub.1992] (Box 227, f. 1)
    - "Competitive Performance of U.S. Industrial Enterprises: A Historical Perspective" for Capital Choices, Michael Porter, ed. [pub. 1992] (Box 185, f. 10)
    - 300 Largest: Basic File-Porter Piece [pub. 1992] (Box 185, f. 11)
    - "Organizational Capabilities and the Economic History of the Industrial Enterprise," [pub. Summer 1992] (Box 185, f. 12-14)
    - "History and Management: Practice and Thought," [pub. 1992] (Box 185, f. 15-17)
    - "The Competitive Performance of the U.S. Industrial Enterprises Since the Second World War," Business History Review [pub. Spring 1994] (Box 227, f. 2-4)
    - "Corporate Growth and Restructuring: a Historical Review," [pub. 1994] (Box 185, f. 18)
    - "Managerial Enterprise and the Entrepreneurial Function," [pub. 1994] (Box 185, f. 19)
    - "Comparable Units for Comparative Institutional Analysis," [pub. 1996] (Box 185, f. 20-21)
    - "The Computer Industry: The First Half Century" [pub. 1997] (Box 186, f. 1)
    - "The Computer Industry: The First Half Century" [pub in Joffie, 1997]: Computer Interviews: Joffie, Hutcheson, McKinny, Akers, 1994-1995 (Box 186, f. 2)
    - "The Computer Industry.. .": Draft, Notes, Research [pub. 1997] (Box 186, f. 3-5)
    - Du Pont, P.S.: American National Biography [pub. 1997] (Box 186, f. 6)
    - A Nation Transformed by Information: Outline, correspondence, and publication records, 1996-2000 (Box 227, f. 6)
    - A Nation Transformed by Information: Big business, 1995 (Box 227, f. 7)
    - A Nation Transformed by Information: Richard John chapter, 1999- circa 2000 (Box 227, f. 8)
    - A Nation Transformed by Information: Drafts and notes (Box 227, f. 9-10)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century Distribution/wholesaling, 1929-1982 (photocopies) (Box 186, f. 7)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Computers: Basic Sources: G.E., 1991 (Box 186, f. 8)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Basic Sources: Japanese Chip Competition, 1989-1990 (Box 186, f. 9)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Basic Sources: PCs, undated (Box 186, f. 10)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Basic Sources: PCs-not used in conclusion, undated (Box 186, f.11)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Basic Sources: Software, 1989-1995 (Box 186, f. 12)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Basic Sources: Work stations, Minis, 1990-1995 (Box 186, f. 13)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Basic Sources: Work stations, Sun, IBM, HP, 1990-1995 (Box 187, f. 1)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Research Material: Computer Industry, 1993-1995 (Box 187, f. 2)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Inventing the Electronic Century: Computers: Datamation-Japanese Companies, 1989-1993 (Box 187, f. 3)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Inventing the Electronic Century: Computers: Datamation, 1980 (Photocopy) (Box 187, f. 4)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Computers: Datamation, 1982 (Photocopy) (Box 187, f. 5)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Computers: Datamation, 1983 (Photocopy) (Box 187, f. 6)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Computers: Datamation, 1984 (Photocopy) (Box 187, f. 7)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Computers: Datamation, 1985 (Photocopy) (Box 187, f. 8)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Computers: Datamation, 1986 (Photocopy) (Box 187, f. 9)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Computers: Datamation, 1988 (Photocopy) (Box 187, f. 10)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Computers: Datamation, 1989 (Photocopy) (Box 187, f. 11)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Computers: Datamation, 1990 (Photocopy) (Box 187, f. 12)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Computers: Datamation, 1991 (Photocopy) (Box 187, f. 13)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Computers: Datamation, 1992 (Photocopy) (Box 187, f. 14)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Computers: Datamation, 1993 (Photocopy) (Box 187, f. 15)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Computers: Datamation, 1995 (Photocopy) (Box 187, f. 16)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Computers, Datamation, 1996 (Photocopy) (Box 187, f. 17)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Computers: Datamation, 1997 (Photocopy) (Box 187, f. 18)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Computers: Datamation: Research Clippings, 1980 (Box 187, f. 19)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Basic Sources: Consumer Electronics, 1981-1985 (Box 188, f. 1)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Basic Sources: Hewlett-Packard, 1989-1994 (Box 188, f. 2)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Basic Sources: Philco, 1935-1981 (Box 188, f. 3)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Basic Sources: Second Level Electronics (Box 188, f. 4)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Basic Sources: Westinghouse, 1968-1992 (Box 188, f. 5)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Basic Sources: US Competition except HP, 1972-1994 (Box 188, f. 6)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Overview and comments, 1998- circa 2001 (Box 223, f. 1)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Chapter 1-4, 2000- circa 2001 (Box 223, f. 2-3)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Chapter 2 and 3, 1972- circa 2001 (Box 223, f. 4-6)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Chapter 2 and 3 with notes, 2000- circa 2001 (Box 223, f. 7)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Draft-Chapter 3: Computers, Mainframes and Minis, March 1998 (Box 188, f. 7)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Draft-Chapter 4: Microcomputers: Recasting the Learning Paths, March 1998 (Box 188, f. 8)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Chapter 4, 2000- circa 2001 (Box 223, f. 7)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Chapter 7, 1999- circa 2001 (Box 224, f. 1)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Chapter 9-11, 1997- circa 2001 (Box 224, f. 2)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Chapter 10, 1998- circa 2001 (Box 224, f. 3)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Chapter 11, 1998- circa 2001 (Box 224, f. 4)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Final Items: Chap. 4,5,6,7, 2000 (Box 188, f. 9)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Critical data for Japanese translation, circa 2001 (Box 224, f. 5)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Tables, statistics, etc., 1985- circa 2001 (Box 224, f. 6)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Sources, 1970-2000 (Box 224, f. 7-8)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Competitors, 1992-1997 (Box 224, f. 9)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Articles/book pages, 1985- circa 2001 (Box 224, f. 10)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Loose research materials, 1980-2001 (Box 224, f. 11-12)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Loose research materials, 1980-2001 (Box 225, f. 1-3)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Harvard Business Review, Mar.-Apr. 2000 (Box 225, f. 4)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: California Management Review, Fall 1990 (Box 225, f. 5)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: International Directory of Company Histories, Vol. 1, 1988 (photocopy) (Box 225, f. 6)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: International Directory of Company Histories, Vol. III, 1991 (photocopy) (Box 225, f. 7)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: International Directory of Company Histories, Vol. V, 1992 (photocopy) (Box 225, f. 8)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Various HBS Working Papers, 1996-1997 (Box 225, f. 9)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Mastering Global Business, Parts 1-10, Financial Times, 1997 (Box 226, f. 1-5)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: World Business, "Wall Street Journal Reports," 1996 (Box 226, f. 6)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: Information revolution, 1998 (Box 226, f. 7)
    - Inventing the Electronic Century: World Game Institute, 1998 (Box 226, f. 8)
    - Business History Around the World [pub. 2003]: Original papers from the colloquia in Milan, October 1998. (Box 228, f. 1-3)
    - Business History Around the World: Items for Milan and book, 1990-1993 (Box 228, f. 4)
    - Business History Around the World: Items for book, 1995 (Box 228, f. 5)
    - Business History Around the World: Loose research materials, 1946-1993 (photocopies) (Box 228, f. 6)
    - Leviathans [pub. 2005]: Preface- Bruce Mazlish, 2001- circa 2005 (Box 228, f. 7)
    - Leviathans: Frank Smith's comments, 2003 (Box 228, f. 8)
    - Leviathans: Multi-national, chapter 1, 2001- ca. 2005 (Box 228, f. 9)
    - Leviathans: Bruce- Global Elite, ca. 2005 (Box 228, f. 10)
    - Leviathans: Kobrin, 2001- circa 2005 (Box 228, f. 11)
    - Leviathans: Sei Yonekura on Japan, 2001- circa 2005 (Box 228, f. 12)
    - "Commercializing High-Technology Industries," Business History Review, 79 [pub. Fall 2005] (Box 228, f. 13)
    - "Response to Richard Sylia's Comments," Capitalism and Society [pub. 2006] (Box 228, f. 14)
    - Shaping the Industrial Century [pub. 2005]: Draft, ca. 2003 (Box 229)
    - Shaping the Industrial Century: Chapter 1- early versions, 1991-2001 (Box 255, f. 1)
    - Shaping the Industrial Century: Chapter 1- early versions, 1991-2001 (Box 255, f. 2)
    - Shaping the Industrial Century: Chapter 1B, 2001-circa 2005 (Box 255, f. 3)
    - Shaping the Industrial Century: Chapter 2, 1987-circa 2005 (Box 255, f. 4)
    - Shaping the Industrial Century: Chapter 2: Challenge of Tech, 1981-circa 2005 (Box 255, f. 5)
    - Shaping the Industrial Century: Final text- Chemicals, Part 1, 1993-circa 2005 (Box 255, f. 6)